它安全么?
Is it safe?
是的, 密室已经被封上了
其他人呢?
Yes. The chamber has been sealed.
Where are the others?
兄弟会现在有的只是陷落的Astrenon
只剩下我们了
The Brotherhood has fallen Astrenon.
We are all that remains
天哪
如果我们死了, 那就....
My God.
If we die, then....
快点!
它们越来越近了!
Hurry!
They're getting closer!
Eleena, 我知道我已经说过了,
不过还是非常感谢你
Eleena, I know I've said this before,
but thank you so much
允许我们留在这里
还帮我们拿来这些材料
for letting us in here,
helping us through the material.
它们实在是太吸引人了
It's been utterly fascinating.
我非常乐意这样做, 博士
非常抱歉这些信息非常凌乱
I'm happy to do it Doctor.
I'm sorry this information is so scattered.
我担心我们同时涉及的项目太多
I'm afraid we were working on
so many projects at once,
以至于会经常拿错相关的材料
that reference materials
tend to get misplaced.
看这
Look at that.
发生什么事了?
What is going on here?
只是开一些小玩笑, McKay
Just having a little fun, McKay.
我们现在能够
重新投入到工作中去么?
Can we get back to work now?
我只是不明白翻看这些历史书
对找到ZPM有什么帮助
I just don't see how running through history
books is gonna find us our ZPM.
好吧
Really.
看到这了么? 这是一张拓片
取自一个古人的修道院
See this? This is a charcoal rubbing,
taken from an Ancient temple,
它大致建成于Weir列出清单的时候
(这里的Weir指15集中返回过去的Weir)
built about the time Weir's list was written.
注意到什么东西比较眼熟了么, 嗯?
Notice anything familiar, hmmm?
这是一个ZPM
瞧, 我们已经很接近了
It's a ZPM.
Look we are close.
比我们以前任何时候都要接近
Closer than we have ever been before.
现在这个星系当中
Now there might very well be hundreds
of Zero Point Modules,
可能藏着数百个ZPM
hidden in this galaxy,
不过我们唯一可以间接确认的那个
就在这里!
but the only one we are remotely
sure of, is here!
这里!
如果你们还想回家
Here!
Now if you ever want to go home.
如果你们还想保卫亚特兰蒂斯
免受幽灵的侵害, 我们就需要找到它
If you ever want to protect Atlantis
from the Wraith, we need to find this.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第16集 兄弟会
Charlie_CZ
他们知不知道那个ZPM
可能在什么地方?
Do they have any information
on where the ZPM could be?
根据传说中所讲述的, 有一个古人
穿过星际之门从亚特兰蒂斯来到那里
According to legend, an Ancient from
Atlantis came through the Stargate
并将一件稀有的财宝托付给了
一伙Sudarian的祭司
and entrusted a sect of Sudarian
priests with a rare treasure,
或者说是potentia
他们是这样叫那东西的
or potentia, as they called it.
那个Lantian人叫他们藏好那个东西
无论如何又不能让幽灵夺去
This Lantian told them to keep it hidden
from the Wraith at all costs.
现在Sudarian人非常崇敬古人
并且把potentia视为
Now the Sudarian people worshipped
the Ancients and considered the potentia,
他们最神圣的物品
their most sacred artifact.
现在可以说他们是完完全全按照
古人的吩咐去做了
Now predictably they did exactly
as the Ancient requested.
那个potentia是....
The potentia being....
ZPM
The ZPM
这么说他们从来没有用过它?
So they wouldn't have used it?
据我所知, 他们只在非常重要的节日
From what I could tell,
they only brought it out of hiding,
才把它从保藏的地点取出来展示
to be displayed on high holidays.
如果他们知道它可以被利用
那我就觉得奇怪了
I'd be surprised if the knew
it could be used,
不过这是一个好消息
and that is good news.
如果他们不知道如何利用它
那么很有可能它还是满的
If they didn't know how to use it,
chances are it's still could be full.
不过坏消息是
在经过幽灵上万年的掠夺之后
The bad news however, is that after
10,000 years of Wraith culling,
Sudarian人的文明在本质上已经灭绝了
Sudarian society is essentially extinct.
星球上现有的文明
都是后来重新发展起来的
The planet's inhabitants are only
at a renaissance level of development,
不过在我们的一些帮助下
我想他们还是可以取得一些进展的
but with the help of some of our gear,
I really think they could make some headway.
好吧, 我信了
少校, 带你的人再去一次Dagan
Alright. I'm sold.
Major, take your team back to Dagan.
看看你们能不能
为我们搞到一张回家的票
See if you can get us a ticket home.
伤处还在疼么?
Does it still pain you?
你们走吧
Leave us.
你有什么要跟我说的?
What do you have for me?
Atlantians人回到了Dagan
The Atlantians have returned to Dagan.
你确信?
You're sure?
噢, 是的
我们的线人刚刚报告的
Oh yes.
Our operative just checked in.
这距他们离开那里只有12小时
他们一定离它已经很近了
It's only been 12 hours since they left.
They must be getting close to it.
我们知不知道那到底是什么?
Do we have any idea what it is yet?
我们了解得稍微多一点
We know a little more.
很多眼线一直以来都在远处盯着
那些亚特兰蒂斯队伍
Many offworld spies have been keeping
a close eye on the Atlantian teams, from afar.
这是我们好不容易才得到的第一个
跟他们如此接近的星球
This is the first planet we've managed
to get this close to them.
他们在寻找一个
Lantian时代的能源
They're looking for a Lantian
era power source.
Cowens首领在那个队伍中么?
Is Chief Cowens on the team?
现在不在 他要先完成别的任务
即使他在队伍中
Not yet. His priorities are elsewhere.
Even if he was.
他也不会发给你消息的
He would never send you.
亚特兰蒂斯人最需要的是
更多的能量
The last thing the Atlantians
need is more power.
让我去那个星球
不管Cowens愿不愿意
Get me on that planet.
With or without Cowens blessing.
我不知道发生了什么
它就是不工作了
I don't know how it happened,
it just stopped working.
我恢复了其中一些功能
不过仍然有一些功能还没有恢复
I got some of the functionality back,
it still isn't doing everything it used to.
好吧, 如果不再有人在这个
有一万年历史的设备附近
Yes well, maybe if people stopped insisting in such close proximity to 10, 000 year
on having food and liquid old equipment.
嗨! 我们已经很小心了
不是我们导致的这个问题
Hey! We're very careful.
We're not the problem here.
是的 啊 哈
Yes. Ah ha.
你碰了什么?
What did you touch?
没有, 我什么也没有碰
Nothing. I didn't touch anything.
重新校对一下
Revise it.
这是什么??
What is this??
我不知道我们有深空探测器
I didn't know we had deep space sensors.
是的 没人知道
Yes, well, no-one did.
据我所知, 它们同其它主要系统一起
From what I can tell, they've been running
silently in the background,
默默的在后台运行
along with our other primary systems.
在后台?
In the background?
是的
Yes
那么为什么又突然跳到了前台?
So why this sudden leap to the foreground?
问得很好
Excellent question.
我们还不知道答案, 是不是?
We don't have an answer for that yet, do we?
到现在为止, 还不知道
Not as of yet, no.
好了, 说出来让我参考参考
不要把我当外人
Ok, well keep me in the loop.
噢, 没有把你当外人
Oh. You are the loop.
那么现在是不是可以说
Now isn't that a nice thing to say.
我还是很欢迎你继续与我同行
You're more than welcome
to continue walking with me,
不过你是不是还有一些事情需要去做?
but if there's something you need to do?
是的 是的
Yes. Yes.
他们称自己为Quidosen
They call themselves the Quidosen.
一个由15个修道士所组成的兄弟会
A brotherhood of 15 monks,
他们唯一的使命就是
保护Potentia, 或者说是 ZPM的安全
whose sole occupation
was to keep the Potentia, or ZPM safe.
这很吸引人
That's fascinating.
是的, 很吸引人
Yes, fascinating.
请继续
Please go on.
这15个人所组成的兄弟会
是由一个首领
The brotherhood of the 15,
consisted of a master handler,
5个保卫者以及9个石头携带者所组成
5 protectors and 9 stone carriers.
他们最害怕的就是
整个兄弟会
Their greatest fear was that
the entire brotherhood
在某一天会被幽灵抓去
might one day be culled by the Wraith,
这样就永远不会有人找到那个ZPM
which would result in the ZPM
going missing forever.
没人可以找到, 是的, 不过它也不会
落入到敌人的手中
Missing yes, but it would not fall
into enemy hands.
他们被委托来保管那个ZPM
They were entrusted with the ZPM.
他们所希望的就是就是有一天
Lantians将会回来收回它
Their hope was that one day
the Lantians would return to reclaim
并且作为完成任务的报答
付给Sudarian人民一些奖赏
it and reward the Sudarian people
for completing their task.
于是他们留下暗示 线索
即使兄弟会被消灭...
So they left hints, clues,
should the brotherhood be destroyed.
是这样
That's right.
祭司们制作了9个带有标记的石头
把它们放在一起时
The priests created 9 stone markers,
that when united,
就会揭示最后
are supposed to reveal
the final resting place
Quidosen保藏宝物的地方
of the Quidosan's protected treasure.
到目前为止我们只找到了三个
So far we've only found three.
这些石头上刻有很多点和线
The etching on the rocks,
involve many lines and dots.
我们认为这是一张地图
We think it's a map.
嗯, 令人惊奇
Hmmm. Amazing.
确实是
It is actually.
这看起来好像是古人的编号系统
This looks like an Ancient
numbering system.
我们也是这样想的
That's what we thought.
据我们所知
应该是数字3, 6和7
From what we can tell,
the numbers 3, 6 and 7.
干得漂亮
Excellent work.
I mean, seriously,
认真地说, 我已经被深深地打动了
I'm very impressed here.
你实在是太友好了, 博士
That's very kind of you Doctor.
你们是在哪里找到它们的?
Where did you find them?
这个建筑过去实际上是
他们的修道院
This building used to be their
monastery, actually.
我们把在这里找到的一些信息
凑合在一起
We pieced together some of the
information we found here ,
然后依此找到了6号和7号石头
and tracked down the number
6 and 7 stones.
另外我们在一次不相关的挖掘中
找到了3号石头
We found the number 3 stone
on an unrelated dig,
就是在上周
just last week.
就是说如果我们找到了石头
我们就找到了地图
So if we find the stones, we find the map.
是的, 很对
Yes, exactly.
你看到这个了么?
You see this?
设计中的一部分?
Part of the design?
我并不认为石头上有些部分的存在
仅仅是为了美观
I don't think anything on these stones
is there for just aesthetics.
每块石头在不同的位置
都有一块凹陷的区域
Yeah. Each of the stones has a different
part of the grid embossed.
表示在最后组合的时候
各自所处的位置
Signifying where it's correct placing should
be in the final configuration.
很对
Exactly.
然后呢?
So what?
然后? 噢! 你有地图么?
So what? Oy! Do you have a map?
你们是在哪里找到它们的?
Ok, where did you find them?
我们在这里找到七号石头
We found the seventh
stone here.
在这里找到六号
以及最近...
The sixth stone here,
and most recently we stumbled
在这里找到了三号石头
on the number 3 stone, here.
你们可能不知道找到它是多么的幸运
You have no idea how lucky a find that was.
我明白了
I see it
博士, 我不太明白....
Doctor, I'm not sure....
他们是根据一个网格来埋藏的
They buried a grid.
瞧, 如果没有三号石头
我们就无法完成这些
Look, we couldn't have done this
without the number three stone.
它, 与七号石头一起
为我们指出了两个相对的角
That, along with the number seven stone,
give us two diagonally opposed corners.
根据这个, 我们就可以精确推断
网格到底有多大
From that, you can extrapolate
exactly how big the grid is,
从而推断出其它石头埋藏的地点
and therefore, where each of the other
stones should be buried.
好吧, 分成两队
让我们开始挖吧
Alright, split up Two teams.
Let's start digging.
你认为他们会找到它么?
Do you think they will find it:?
曾经有很多人从多个不同的星球赶来
寻找Quidosa失落的财宝
Many people from may world's have come
to find the lost city of Quidosa.
你认为他们会找到么?
Do you think they will find it?
我不知道
I do not know.
我们将会等待他们找到那个财宝
然后我们就用武力把它夺走
We'll wait for them to find the treasure,
then we'll take it by force.
除非我下命令, 你的人不能随便行动
明白么?
Your men are not to act
until I give the word, understood?
当然
Absolutely.
我们应该往...嗯...右, 我想
Which would make us, uh, right, I think.
你能够相信我们所取得进展么, Simear
Can you believe the progress
we've made, Simear.
我们为了找这些石头
已经花了多少年了?
How many years have we been
searching for these stones?
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我们不应该帮助他们, Eleena
We should not be helping them, Eleena.
我们在帮他们的时候
他们也在帮助我们
They're helping us as much
as we are helping them.
如果找到了potentia, 他们就会带走它
你必须意识到这一点
They will take the potentia if they find it.
You must see that.
他们是从伟大的城市
亚特兰蒂斯  过来的
They have come to us,
from the great city of Atlantis.
那个15人组成的兄弟会正是为他们
It is for them,
that the brotherhood of the 15,
而保藏那个财宝的
have kept the treasure hidden.
我不相信他们, Eleena
I do not trust them Eleena.
如果你想回到你的村子
而不是帮助我们
If you would rather head back
to your village, than help us.
我不会拦你的
I will not stop you.
过来一下
Just a second.
Eleena!
这会生效的
This is gonna work.
我想会的
I think it just might.
这是Suderian 村庄的布局图
It's a layout of the
Suderian villages.
这座修道院的墙壁
为她守护了一万年
The walls of this monastery have protected
her for 10,000 years.
它很漂亮
It's beautiful.
确实是
不过现在我的眼睛正开着其它地方
It is. And yet my eye is drawn elsewhere.
我希望有一天能够修复它
不过我怕把它弄坏了
I'd like to restore it one day,
but I'm afraid of damaging it.
也许你可以帮助我, 博士
Perhaps you could help me, Doctor.
实际上, 你应该开始叫我Rodney了
Really, you need to start calling me Rodney.
好的
Very well.
我没有让你觉得厌烦吧?
I don't bore you, do I?
不, 不是因为你
我想我从没有这么困过
No, it's not you.
I don't think I've ever been so tired.
你是一个科学家
到现在你还没有习惯么?
You're a scientist.
Are you not used to this by now?
我的那种科学是一种很好的科学
My kind of science is the good
kind of science.
就是那种你可以坐在椅子上
甚至是躺在沙发上
The kind you can do sitting on a chair,
or even laying on a couch.
在古人的城市中生活
是种什么滋味, Rodney?
What was it like growing up in the city
of the ancestors, Rodney?
抱歉?
Sorry?
亚特兰蒂斯
Atlantis.
噢, 不, 不, 不
Oh, no, no, no.
我们是来自于另外一个星系中
被称作为地球的行星
We come from a planet called Earth
in an altogether different galaxy.
我们只是最近才把
亚特兰蒂斯当作我们的家
We only just recently made
Atlantis our home.
多久以前?
How recently?
实际上只有几个月
A matter of months really.
嗯, 你困了
睡吧, 我就不打扰你了
Mmmm. You're tired.
Do not let me keep you from sleep.
如果你坚持, 我会, 嗯...好吧
If you insist, I'll, uh..ok
我要上床睡觉了
I'm heading to bed.
哪个床?
Which bed might that be.
什么?
What?
我想Eleena或许是
有点爱上你了
I think Eleena might have
a little crush on you Doctor.
是么?
She does?
我们都看得很清楚
It is very clear to us all.
是么?
It is?
非常清楚, 除了你, 显然
Well everyone but you, apparently.
我应该...你确信么?
Well, should I...Are you sure about this?
是的, 非常确信
Yeah, pretty sure.
我应该怎么做?
What should I do?
你不知道怎么做?
You don't know what to do?
我知道最后应该怎么做
I know what to do eventually.
我的意思是, 我应该说些什么
说些什么, 就在今晚
I mean, should I say something.
Something tonight.
告诉你是什么, Valentino
(意大利裔的美国演员,
以扮演浪漫的主角而出名)
Tell you what, Valentino.
Wait till tomorrow.
等到明天, 在你获得一些休息之后
你会更加投入到你的游戏中去的
You'll be more on your game,
after you get some rest.
好吧, 好吧, 很好的答案
晚安
Right. Right. Good answer. Goodnight.
这看起来不像是一幅地图
我想我以前认为的不对
It doesn't look much like a map.
I guess I was wrong.
嗯, 有可能
尽管, 嗯
Hmmm. Possibly.
Although, um.
仅仅因为最开始你认为
它是一幅地图
Well, you know, just because
you originally thought it was a map,
并不就能说你最初的假设
不好或者不对
doesn't make your initial assumption
bad or incorrect.
不对, 是的, 不过这是一个很好的猜想
Well incorrect, yes, but it was a good guess.
对不起?
I'm sorry?
你非常非常聪明和有魅力
You are very, very smart and attractive
and whatknot,
有太多太多赞美你的话
即时是当....
and you've got a lot of things going for you,
even when things don't....
一切都好吧?
Is everything alright?
是的, 一切都好
很好
Yes, everything's great.
It's great.
一切都很好
为什么会不好呢?
Everything's quite well,
why wouldn't it be?
你确信我们是在正确的地方?
You sure we're in
the right place?
我们已经将挖掘的区域扩大了一倍
不过我们仍然没有找到任何东西
We've almost doubled the size of the digsite
and we haven't found anything yet.
这应该是正确的地点
It's got to be the right place.
其它八块石头都正好在我们
预见的地方出现
The other eight stones were exactly
where we thought they would be.
这一个为什么要有不同呢?
Why would this be any different?
少校!
Major!
告诉我你找到了一块石头
Tell me you found a stone.
不全是, 长官, 不过我想McKay
应该来看看这个
Not quite sir, but I think McKay
should take a look at this.
这上面是兄弟会的标志
It carries the sign of the brotherhood.
我想是古人的语言
你知道是什么意思么?
I think it's in Ancient. Can you read it?
是警告
It is warning.
只有兄弟会中的15个人
才允许进入这个密室
It is only brotherhood the 15th
bidden chamber.
Quidosen的成员
Of that windows.
什么密室?
What chamber?
谁想第一个下?
看起来, 好像是, Sheppard?
So, who wants to go first.
Seems, sorta like, Sheppard might?
我们意料不到比这更好的了
We couldn't have planned it any better.
噢! 慢一点, Ford
Oh! Easy Ford"""
好了, 他下来了
Alright, he's down.
好了, 我留在这里
看住不让其它东西下来
Alright, I'll stay here,
keep an eye on the Descender.
警惕点
Stay sharp.
如果有什么有趣的东西
我会让你知道的
I'll let you know if anything
interesting happens.
看到这了么? 这就是完整的图案
Do you see this? This is the whole pattern.
第九块石头必须与中间的
这个图案吻合
The ninth stone must integrate
into this Wraith centrepiece.
我想我们可以排除地图的想法了
I believe we can rule out a map.
好吧, 有什么想法?
Alright, any ideas?
我正在想
I'm getting there.
是的, 集合你的队伍
开往第七区
Yes, get your team together and
head off to section seven.
Weir博士,  Weir博士
我终于可以将我们的电脑接入到
Dr Weir. Dr Weir. I was finally
able to interface our computers
亚特兰蒂斯的远程探测器了
with the Atlantian long range sensors.
非常好
Excellent.
有身份不明的飞船
There's an unidentified craft,
大小近似于幽灵的小飞船
正朝我们的城市飞来
about the size of a Wraith dart,
heading for the city.
什么?
What?
是的
Yes.
抱歉
探测器数天以前就发现了它
Sorry.
The sensors picked it up day's ago,
只是我现在才弄清楚
but it's taken me until now,
它们正试图告诉我们的信息
to finally decipher what
they're trying to tell us.
小飞船 这怎么可能?
A dart. How is that possible?
也许它经过了改造
以便尽快赶到这里
Well, perhaps it was modified
to get here as quickly as possible.
母船仍然在数光年之外
The hive ships are light years away still.
它可能利用了邻近的星际之门
Well it could have used
neighbouring stargate
然后以最快速度飞向我们
and been flying towards
us at maximum speed,
自从幽灵探测到我们在这里以来
ever since Wraith discovered
that we were here.
按照它现有的速度
27分钟后它就会到达这里
At it's current velocity,
it'll be here in 27 minutes.
我们需要让我们的飞船升空
We need to get jumpers in the air.
什么, 你不相信什么?
What, what don't you believe?
这是星际之门的拨号地址
六个符号, 星际之门的地址
It's a gate address.
A six symbol, gate address.
星际之门的符号?
Gate symbols?
我看到了, 是的
I see them now. Yes.
你认出这个地址了么?
Do you recognise the address?
没有
No.
我对这些文字也不熟悉
I am not familiar with this world, either.
这就是说第九个石头
在另外一个星球上
So the ninth stone's on another planet.
他死了么?
Is he dead?
不, 只是昏迷了
他数小时内不会醒来
No, just unconscious.
He'll be like that for hours.
很好, 我们将等他们出现....
Excellent. We'll wait for them to appear....
把武器放下, Ford中尉
Put the weapon down, LT Ford.
Ford!
Sheppard少校
Major Sheppard.
我想中尉恐怕不得不
离开一会儿了
I'm afraid the Lt has had to
step away for a moment.
那是谁?
Who's that?
不可能
It can't be.
听起来好像是....
It sounds like....
Koya!!
很奇怪吧?
Surprised?
你还活着
You're alive.
到现在为止, 是这样
As far as I can tell.
你真的认为一颗打在肩膀上的子弹
就可以杀了我么?
Did you actually think a single bullet
to the shoulder would kill me?
我总是想你会更聪明一些
I always thought you were smarter than that.
你对Ford做了些什么?
What did you do to Ford?
他很好
He's fine.
那么, 你想要什么?
Then, what do you want?
同你一样, 少校
Quindosam失落的财宝
The same as you , Major.
The lost treaure of the Quindosam.
那对你有什么用?
What possible use could that be to you?
Daganian已经告诉我们
这个东西, ZPM,
The Daganians have informed
us that this ZPM,
不管怎样
是一个强大的能源
whatever it may be,
is an object of great power,
而强大的能源对所有人都有用
特别是Genii
and great power is of use to all people.
Especially the Genii.
Simear!
他们给我们一个很大的回报
Eleena
They offered us a great reward,
Eleena,
他们同意让我们保存这个财宝
如果我们....
They agreed to let us keep the treasure,
if we....
它们对你没用Koya
ZPM只能在Atlantis工作
They're no use to you Koya.
ZPM's only work on Atlantis.
也许吧  不过我倾向于听到
这句话是由Genii的科学家说出的
Perhaps. But I prefer hearing
that from a Genii scientist.
我们还没有拥有它
我们还没有找到第九块石头
We do not have it yet.
We have not found the ninth stone.
我们现在具有
你们所无法想象的巨大的优势
We have an unbelievably large
tactical advantage over you.
现在如果我愿意的话
我可以封住密室上来的出口
Now if you would rather
I just cover the mouth
然后忘掉整件事情
of the chamber up and forget
about the whole thing,
我简直是太想这样做了
I'm more than willing to consider it.
她是对的 我们更接近
不过我们仍然没有得到
She's right. We're closer,
but we're not there yet.
第九块石头藏在
另外一个行星上
Look, the ninth stone
is hidden on another planet.
现在我们有的
只有星际之门的地址
All we have, is the gate address.
McKay博士 很高兴又听到
你那讨厌的声音
Dr McKay. So wonderful to hear
your grating voice again.
手臂怎么样了?
How's the arm?
你是想继续说讽刺的话
还是希望找到ZPM?
You wanna keep trading barbs?
Or you wanna find the ZPM?
把我拉上来
我会帮你找到它
Look, lift me out of here,
I'll help you find it,
不过你答应要让我的队员离开
but then you let my team go.
住嘴, McKay
Shut up, McKay.
你有更好的主意?
You got a better idea?
没有
No.
你同不同意?
Do we have a deal or not?
你和那两个Daganian人将被拉出来
同时还有每个人的武器和无线电
You and two Daganians will be raised out.
Along with everyone's weapons and radio's.
剩下的人留在那里
The rest of you will remain here.
如果McKay博士找到了ZPM
其他人就可以走了
If Dr McKay finds the ZPM,
the others will be let go.
我向你保证
I give you my word.
好吧, 我们接受他的承诺
Well, we have his word.
我想我们没有更多地选择了
我就要上来了!
I don't see that we have much choice.
I'm coming up!
我们已经将大部分人
封闭在住处了
We've got the general population
confined to quarters.
但愿他们不会受到伤害
Let's hope they're out of harms way.
Sheppard有没有回话?
Any word from Sheppard yet?
没有, 我没法联系到他
他的整个队伍都不在无线电旁
No, I haven't been able to reach him.
His entire team is off radio.
它仍然在以非常快的速度接近
It's still closing in very fast.
谁将去飞第三艘飞船?
Who are we going to get
to fly the third jumper?
我把它开到大陆, 然后开回来
没有坠毁已经是不错了
I can barely make it there and back
to the mainland, without crashing.
最后再说一次, 我是一个医生
不是一个嗜血的战斗机飞行员!
For the last time, I'm a Doctor,
not a bloody fighter pilot!
一艘幽灵的飞船在十分钟之内
就会飞临城市的上空
A Wraith dart is gonna be all over
this city inside of ten minutes,
而仅有的真正的战斗机飞行员
却在其他星球
and are only real fighter pilot is offworld.
对于我来说, 最希望的就是
尽我们所能构建起最好的防御
I for one, would like to mount
the best defence we can.
很好
Brilliant.
二号离开了
所有三艘都出发了
Number two is away. All three are out.
祝你好运, Carson
Good luck Carson.
谢谢, 我会需要的
Thanks, I'll need it.
没有效
It's not working.
再试一次
Try it again.
我已经试了两次
逆序和正序
Look, I've tried it twice.
Backwards and forwards.
我们以前也玩过这个游戏, McKay
We've played this game
before McKay.
试试其它组合
Try some other combination
of the same symbols.
你在开玩笑?
Are you joking?
你知不知道这会要多久?
Have you any idea how long
that would take?
他是对的
有720种地址组合
He's right.
There's 720 possible gate addresses.
这是浪费时间
It's a waste of time.
你说过这个地址是第九块石头的位置
You said the address was the location
of the ninth stone.
一定是
这个谜题已经有10,000年了
Look, it has to be.
The puzzle is 10,000 years old.
也许那个星际之门已经不存在了
Maybe the gate doesn't exist anymore.
实际上, 在银河系中
有些文明会埋掉他们的星际之门
Look, back in the milky way,
some cultures actually bury their gates,
认为它们毫无用处
to render them useless.
可能是其它的
假如这些不是星际之门的符号呢
That's something else.
What if these aren't stargate symbols.
看看它们, 还有可能是什么, 哼??
Look at them What else could they be, huh??
实际上, 这些符号可能跟
星际之门没有关系
Actually, these symbols may not
be gate related.
真的么? 你是怎么想的?
Really? What are you thinking?
先生们, 它三十秒后
就会出现在你们视野中
Gentlemen, you should have visual
in 30 seconds.
准备好了么?
You ready?
没有, 我没有准备好
No, I'm not ready.
你会做得很好的
You're gonna do fine.
可以做得足够好么?
Is fine gonna be good enough?
正向你们飞来
Coming right at you.
你看到它了么?
Do you see it yet?
还没有, 我看不到它在哪里
Not yet. I can't see it anywhere.
亚特兰蒂斯
Markham和Smith已经被干掉了
Atlantis. Markham and Smith
have been taken out.
这座修道院过去是兄弟会中
15位祭司生活的地方
This monastery is where the 15 priests
of the brotherhood used to live.
这幅壁画是一张地图
The mural here is a map.
记录了当时Suderia的布局
我以前应该想到这一点
A layout of Suderia as it was in their time.
I should have thought of this before.
Suderians人非常崇拜Lantian古人
See, the Suderians worshipped
the Lantian ancestors.
星际之门被认为是一个神圣的入口
同时也包括它的符号
The Stargate was considered a sacred portal
and it's symbols, religious icons.
所有36个星际之门的符号
都被编入进来
All 36 gate symbols are incorporated.
这么说将这些符号与石头联系起来....
So connect the symbols to the stones....
然后你就可以用三角测量法
找到中心石头埋藏的地点
And you should be able to triangulate
where the centre stone is buried.
你真是一个天才
You're a genius.
谢谢 Rodney
Thank you Rodney.
好了, 我们都非常感动
不过让我们开始干吧, 嗯?
Yes ok, we're all very impressed,
but let's get on with it, huh?
把它打下来!
Shoot it down!
它在城市的正中央
我无法下手
It's right in the middle of the city,
I don't have a clean shot.
它在做什么?
What's it doing?
在扫描我们
It's scanning us.
哼
Huh.
我本希望可以稍微缩小一点范围
I was hoping it would narrow
the area down a little more.
这值得一试
Well, it's worth a shot.
地图上所标示的地区有多大?
How big an area does that
represent on the map.
几平方英里
Several square miles.
等等 这是他们符号中的一部分
Hold on a second. It's part of their symbol.
15的记号 是的
The mark of the 15. Yes.
什么?
What?
这是一个15线图形 15线
It's a 15 line symbol. 15 lines.
九条线在外面
Nine lines on the outside.
代表着九个石头的携带者
Representing the stone carriers.
六条在里面
Six on the inside.
代表着五个保卫者和首领
Representing the five protectors
and the master handler.
你知道那是哪里么?
Do you know where that is?
是的, 我可以带你去那
Yes, I can take you there.
别忙
抓紧了! 再等一秒钟
Hold tight! One more second.
好的
Yes.
不是我们干的
至少我认为不是我们干的
We didn't do that.
At least I don't think we did.
不管发生了什么, 它已经死了
亚特兰蒂斯, 我们把它干掉了
Well whatever happened, it's dead.
Atlantis, we have a kill.
这是个好消息, 飞船2号
现在回来吧
Good news Jumper 2. Now head on home.
给我一把小刀
Someone give me a knife.
你们都有枪呢
给我一把小刀
You all have guns. Someone give me a knife.
去吧
Go ahead.
Rodney!
这个地图并不是在告诉我们
应该到哪里去找那块中心石头
It's not a map to where
the centre stone is,
那块中心石头实际上就在这里
瞧
it is where the centre stone is. Look.
我们已经找全了
We have all the pieces.
恭喜你, McKay博士
你们可以继续活下去了
Congratulations Dr McKay. You may live yet.
没指望了
没有什么暗门或者密道
This is pointless.
No trap doors or hidden passageways.
也许这里不只一个出口, 少校
There may be more than
one way in here Major.
当你试图隐藏一个密室时
你并不会想在那个地方
When you're trying to hide a chamber,
you don't think much of entrances
设置多个走道和出口
and exits all over the damn place.
你情愿就坐在那里
等着他们回来?
You'd rather just sit here
and wait for them to come back?
你们有什么可以派得上用场的东西?
What have you got
that we can use?
我有两块干粮, 一些弹药,
以及一些医疗用品
I got a couple of MRE's, some ammo,
some med supplies.
这还可以
That's a start.
我有两个闪光弹
我想可能还有用
I've got a couple of flash bangs.
I think that's about it though.
闪光弹?
Flash bangs?
是的, 有点像手榴弹
拉开扣环, 按下引信
Well, kind of like, grenades.
Pull the pin, depress the trigger.
一旦你激发引信 大概1.5秒之后
Once you let the spoon pop,
you've got about 1.5 seconds,
整个房间就会充满
亮度为240万烛光的闪光
before the room's filled with
2.4 million candle power,
它同时还会发出
175分贝的巨大声响
and a bang that's rated at 175 decibels.
可以让没有保护好
眼睛和耳朵的人
Stun anyone with their
eyes and ears open,
眩晕大概10秒钟
for about ten seconds.
你在做什么?
你准备把我们从这里挖出去么?
What are you doing?
You gonna dig us out of here?
差不多吧
过来帮帮我
Something like that.
Come over here and give me a hand.
嘿, 你还想要Sora回去么?
难道我们的协议只是这些?
Hey, you want Sora back?
Is that what this is all about?
Sora知道她在做什么
比大多数人都清楚
Sora knew what she was doing,
moreso than most of the men.
而且, Genii从来不跟恐怖分子
签订协议
Besides, the Genii do not make
deals with terrorists.
恐怖分子? 是你袭击我们!
Terrorists? You attacked us!
那也是在你们先到我们的星球上
设计埋伏我们之后
After you ambushed us on our own world.
这真是太疯狂了
This is crazy.
我们大家都是想保护自己的人民
We're both just trying to protect
our people.
很对
不过如果把你的人民作为目标
That is correct.
But if making your people a target,
可以为我的人民赢得更多的时间的话
这样做还是值得的
buys my people more time,
it will have been worth it.
听着....
Listen....
我不想再跟你争论这个了, 博士!
I don't wanna discuss it
any further Doctor!
找到ZPM, 然后你们就都可以
会到亚特兰蒂斯
Find the ZPM and you can
all return to Atlantis.
如果失败了 协议就自动终止
Fail and the deal's off.
到底发生了什么?
So what happened out there?
正当我们可以射击的时候
它自己爆炸了
As soon as we had a clean shot,
it self destructed.
为什么?
Why?
女士, 我不知道
我认为它到这里不是来战斗的
Ma'am. I have no idea.
I don't think it came here to fight.
它看起来对我们的飞船也没有兴趣
It didn't seem that interested in the jumpers,
除非我们挡住了它飞向城市的路时
except for when we were blocking
it's way to the city.
幽灵的这种飞船并不是
远程战斗机
Darts are not long range fighters.
事实上它这么远只身前来
应该是为了侦查
The fact it came so far alone.
It was a scout.
那它为什么要自毁呢?
侦查不就意味着要传送信息么
Well why would it self destruct?
Scouts are mean't to relay information.
它确实传送了信息
But it did relay information.
看, 就在它爆炸之前
那艘飞船一直在传送数据
Look, just before it exploded,
the Dart was transmitting data.
我想你不能....
I don't suppose you could....
至少现在不行
Not any time soon, at least.
我们可以判断信息是发往哪里么?
Can we determine where it was sending it?
我可以引导远程探测器指向那块区域
能不能给我几个小时?
I could direct long range sensors to that area.
Give me a couple of hours?
我想我们应该把石头放在基座上
I just assumed that we'd place
the stones on the pedestal,
然后让人把手掌
have someone put their hands
放在这个掌印上
幸运的话, 我们就可以得到ZPM
on the palm prints and hopefully
we'd get the ZPM.
现在的问题是, 我们应该按照
什么顺序来摆放这些石头?
The question is,
what order do we put the stones in?
我认为直接依次摆放即可
I think it's pretty straight forward.
现在没有什么是很直接的!
你认为应该是什么?
Well, nothing's been straightforward yet!
What makes you think this would be?
只有最后一块石头上的凹槽
才跟中心位置对应
The last stone is the only one with grooves
that match the centre position.
然后呢?
So?
然后它就可以顺顺贴贴的放在那个位置
接着完成整个图案并拿到 ZPM
So it fits snugly into place.
Complete the pattern and get the ZPM.
都到这个地步了
他们还会玩什么把戏?
Why would they continue to play
games at this point?
我想你并没有真正理解
这些人是怎么想的
I really don't think you understand
how these people thought.
McKay, 不要拖延时间了
McKay, stop stalling.
我并不是拖延时间, 我只是认为
我们需要看清事实....
I'm not stalling, I just think we need
to consider the fact....
Prenos, 请你过去摆好石头
然后拿到ZPM
Prenos, arrange the stones and retrieve
the ZPM please.
McKay!
你要我做什么?
What do you want me to do?
这是什么?
What's this?
他死了 你知道这会发生的
He's dead. You knew this would happen.
是的, 是的我知道
Yes, yes I did.
事实上, 我正要跟你说
In fact, I was in the middle
of telling you as much,
正在这时你却让他去激活基座
when you ordered him to activate
the pedestal.
是你杀了他, 不是我
Look, you killed him, not me.
这些石头的正确顺序到底是什么?
What's the correct order of the stones?
现在我也不知道
I'm not sure yet.
好吧, 你现在有四次尝试的机会
Well you'll have four chances to get it right.
你先去
You go first.
一旦你想开始....
Any time you wanna start....
我在想, 我在想...
I'm thinking. I'm thinking.
好吧, 我们试了从一到九
Right, we tried one to nine.
谢谢, 是的
Thankyou, yes.
那试试从九到一如何?
How about nine to one?
也许, Prenos是对的
Possibly, look Prenos was right.
中心石头是唯一那个可以
放在这个地方的
The centre stone is the only
one that locks into place.
所有其它的必须已到周围去
All the others must move around it.
我在想一种组合
I'm just trying to think
of a combination
可以让五处于中间
that makes sense with
five in the middle.
十五 一定是跟15, 9或者5有关
Fifteen. It's gotta have something
to do with 15, or 9 or 5.
别说了, 求求你
我正在思考
Shut up, please. I'm trying to think.
我不会住嘴的, Rodney
我的命就押在这上面了
I'm not gonna shut up Rodney,
my life's at stake.
很对, 既然这样就请安静一下
让我想想怎么救你!
Exactly. So simmer down and let me save it!
听过这种说法么?
两个脑袋比一个要聪明
Ever heard the term,
two heads are better than one?
这是公众的误解
It's a common misconception.
给我一把枪, 我想自杀!
Give me the gun and I'll shoot him myself!
你们花的时间已经太多了
做出选择然后开始
This is taking too long. Choose and go.
怎么, 你急着去投胎?
What, you got somewhere you gotta be?
做出选择然后开始!
Choose and go!
我没有主意
I got nothing.
谢谢你鼓舞人心的话
Thanks for the pep talk.
从九到一, 我能想到的只有这个
Nine to one, that's all I can think of.
好吧, 退后
Ok, step back.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我还没有死
I'm not dead yet.
是的, 抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
少校, 开始吧!
Major. Now!
我知道了!
I got it!
什么?
What?
15人组成的brotherhood
The brotherhood of 15.
数字1到9可以被放在一个
3乘以3的格子里
The numbers 1-9 can be put
in a three by three grid,
并且在每个方向加起来都等于15
so they add up to 15 in every direction.
噢, 你是对的! 你是怎么知道的?
Oh, you're right! How did you know that?
这曾经在mensa的测试中出现过
It was on a mensa test.
你是mensa的成员?
You're a member of mensa?
不, 不过我参加过测试
No, but I took the test.
什么时候?
When?
我现在不想谈这个, Rodney
I don't wanna talk about his now Rodney?
好的, 好的
Right, right.
OK. 2, 9, 4
Ok. 2, 9, 4.
7, 5, 3...6,1,8.
就是这, 应该就是这样
7, 5, 3...6,1,8. That's it, that's gotta be it.
祝你好运
Good luck.
到底发生什么了?
What the hell just happened?
你还好吧?
Are you ok?
是的, 谢谢你
Yes, thankyou.
抱歉Rodney, 我没法告诉你
即将发生什么
Sorry Rodney, I had no way of telling
you what was coming.
我的眼睛! 我的眼睛什么都看不见了
My eyes? I need my eyes for seeing.
去拿ZPM, Rodney.
Get the ZPM, Rodney.
这是一个小小的奇迹
我居然还能够辨认出轮廓
It's a small miracle
I can still make out shapes.
我想说的就是这些
That's all I'm saying.
不要看我
Don't look at me.
好吧, 我们要从这里出去
Alright, we're getting out of here.
大约一小时后
我们会让村民把你拉上去
We'll send the villagers to pick you up
in about an hour.
现在最聪明的做法就是把我杀掉
The smart thing would be to kill me now.
你是对的 告诉你吧
我也希望这样做会对将来有所好处
You're right. I tell you what,
I'm gonna want points for this in the future.
不过如果你胆敢再这样做的话
我一定会杀了你的 明白?
But if you ever do this again,
I will kill you. Deal?
都还好吧?
We good?
是的, 直到我能够看见
Yeah, as far as I can see.
我们出去
Let's move out.
我简直无法相信, 你从来没有提起
任何关于Mensa的事情
I can't believe you never mentioned
the Mensa thing.
我接受了测试 不过我从来没有加入
I took the test. I never joined.
你通过了?
But you passed?
是的
Yes.
好吧, 你知道, 我们在亚特兰蒂斯
也有一个题目
Well you know, we have a chapter on Atlantis
Rodney, Rodney. 拉绳子吧
Rodney, Rodney. Up the rope.
我想我们从来没有找到
这么好的东西
I thought we'd never find one
of those things.
我今晚一定会睡得很甜的
I'm gonna sleep pretty soundly tonight.
我可不行 我必须整晚工作
让每个系统都重新运转起来
Not me. I'm gonna be up all night getting
every system I can, back on line.
Eleena, 我想我们真不知道
该如何报答你
Eleena, I don't think we will ever
be able to properly repay you for this.
你们没必要报答我
You won't have to.
对不起?
I'm sorry?
好了, 好了, 放松, 放松!
Alright. Alright, easy. Easy!
Eleena? 你跟Genii人串通好了?
Eleena? You involved the Genii?
这跟Genii人没有任何关系
我是新一届brotherhood的成员
This has nothing to do with the Genii.
I am a member of the new brotherhood.
那这是干什么?
What is this about?
数十代人以前, 在一次残酷的洗劫之后
brotherhood被消灭了
Ten generations ago, after a severe culling,
the brotherhood was destroyed.
我们当中的很多人找到了他们的笔记
并下决心要完成
Many of us found their writings
and decided to try and complete
古人交付给我们的任务
the task handed down to us by the ancestors.
我就是新的首领
I am the new master handler.
我们要谢谢你们帮我们找到了Potentia
We thank you for helping us
find the Potentia.
不过它必须再次被保藏起来
But it must go into hiding again.
我们就是来自古人的城市
那个ZPM就是留给我们的
We come from the city of the ancestors.
That ZPM was intended for us.
不, 你们只是住在 Atlantis
你们并不是古人
No. You live in Atlantis,
but you are not the ancestors.
你跟她说了什么?
What did you tell her?
如果我们不把这个ZPM拿回去
亚特兰蒂斯就会陷落
Atlantis might fall if we don't take
this ZPM back.
那样的话你们这样做就毫无意义了
Then it would serve no purpose.
你认为古人希望看到的就是这个?
You really think the ancestors
would have wanted that?
我们都不知道他们的计划
None of us can know their plan.
他们并没有什么计划
They don't have a plan.
你认为被幽灵袭击
并且被赶出这个星系
You think getting attacked by the Wraith
and getting chased out of the galaxy
也是他们所计划的么?
is something they planned for?
Eleena, 你这样想
实在是有点聪明过头了....
Eleena, you're far too smart to think that....
potentia将会被藏到另外一个星球
The potentia will be put into
hiding on another world.
当古人回来的时候
我们的人民就会得到丰厚的回报
When the ancestors return,
our people will be greatly rewarded.
Eleena, 那可能让你
觉得有点难以置信
Eleena, you can't believe that.
这样, 跟我们一起回去
我会证明给你看的
Well, come back with us.
Let me prove it to you.
事情应该就是这样
现在你们应该走了
This is how it must be.
Now it is time for you to leave.
你们试图解释了么?
Did you try to explain?
我试过了 相信我, 我们试过了
I tried. Believe me, we tried.
我们本可以用上它的
We could have used it.
当然我们可以
Of course we could
不, 你们不明白
当你们还在其它星球的时候
No, you don't understand.
While you were offworld,
一艘幽灵的飞船飞到我们城市的上空
a Wraith Dart flew over our city.
抱歉?
I'm sorry?
我们失去了一艘飞船
同时还有Markham和Smith
We lost a Jumper,
along with Markham and Smith.
什么?
We what?
而且它还扫描了我们
And it scanned us.
我们刚刚失去了两个在飞船中的人
为什么不早点告诉我
We just lost two of my men in a Jumper
and this is the first time I'm hearing about it?
我试图通过无线电联系你
不过十二小时以来一直联系不上
I tried to reach you, but you've been out
of radio contact for twelve hours.
幽灵的飞船已经向
深空传送了一些信息
Now the Dart sent a transmission
deep into space
并且在我们可以抓住它之前自毁了
and then it self destructed
before we could get to it.
我们用我们的深空探测器
扫描了那片区域...
We scanned the area with our
deep space sensors and...
我们有深空探测器?
We have deep space sensors?
是的, 说来话长
Yeah. It's a long story.
我们还发现了一些更为不安的东西
We found something else rather unsettling.
我已经很不安了
给我看吧
I'm already unsettled. Show me.
那些是什么?
What are those?
幽灵的母船, 一共有三个
系统刚刚分析完....
Wraith Hive ships. 3 of them.
The system analysis just got back....
很好, 他们的目的地是哪里?
Great. Where are they headed?
如果它们保持现有的航向和速度
If they maintain direction and speed,
在两个星期之内就会达到我们的星球
they'll be over our planet
within two weeks.